Tyler Stober

Freelance Creative and Front End Developer

Multidisciplinary designer with a primary background in User Experience, User Interface Design, and Front End Development. In addition, also proficient in Motion and 3D design, rendering a unique technical perspective and collaborator with an in-depth awareness of multiple mediums.



Experience

Contract-based April 2021-Present

Freelance Creative

UX/UI Design & Front-end Development Remote • USA & Europe

Responsibilities include Front & Back End Development, Design Systems, User Experience Design, and User Interface Design. Notable clients include Walgreens, Wish.com, and Havas/Annex. Medium-sized clients include Forma, Hush, Nyla, Gamma Waves. Non-profit and small-sized clients include The Goldin Institute, Artizen.fund, Free Ross DAO, Continuum Capital, and MXML Creative.

Full Time February 2017-April 2021 4 years, 2 months

Walgreens Boots Alliance

Senior Interaction Deisgner Chicago IL, USA

Lead designer and developer for the Walgreens Design Systems, implementing design-lead ownership of foundational components that support Walgreens.com. Front-end developer for the Walgreens.com homepage and designer of Walgreens' functional icons. Leadership role in coordinating efforts between Development, Design, and Accessibility teams, which were previously siloed parts of the organization.

Full Time June 2015 - january 2017 1 year, 7 months

Doejo

Senior Interaction Deisgner Chicago IL, USA

User Experience Design, User Interface Design, Motion Design, and Front-End & WordPress Development. Exclusively working with small-stage startups.

Education

2009 - 2014

University of Cincinnati

College of Deisgn, Arhcitecture, Art and Planning B.S. Graphic Communication Design 2014

Professional Practice Program: alternating semesters of school with semesters of work.

Skills

Development

React

TypeScript

Javascript

Theming

Design Systems/Storybook

Prototyping

CSS-in-JS, CSS, SCSS

CSS Animations

APIs/GraphQL

WebGL/React-three-fiber

Wordpress/PHP

Design

User Interface Design
User Experience Design
Design Systems
Accessibility
3D Modeling
Motion Design

Software

Github

VS Code

Figma

Adobe Creative Suite

Wordpress

Cinema4D

Information

atobertg@gmail.com

Citizenship: United States & Portugal

+(351) 933.394.313

linkedin.com/in/tyler-stober